A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Office of Communications, Advisor on Communications, Office Files of Fred W. Friendly FA616
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Correspondence, 1945-1980; I; 13.8 Cubic Feet
  - Alphabetical, 1955 - 1980; A
    - Martin Luther King Film Project, 1970 (Box 6 (33858), Folder 3)
    - Marx, Groucho, 1967 (Box 6 (33858), Folder 4)
    - Massachusetts Institute of Technology, 1966 - 1979 (Box 6 (33858), Folder 5)
    - Mayer, Martin, 1972 (Box 6 (33858), Folder 6)
    - Meade, Edward J., 1966 - 1976 (Box 6 (33858), Folder 7)
    - Memoranda, miscellaneous Ford Foundation, 1966 - 1980 (Box 6 (33858), Folder 8)
    - Miller, Arthur, 1976 - 1980 (Box 6 (33858), Folder 9)
    - Minow, Newton N., 1966 - 1980 (Box 6 (33858), Folder 10)
    - Morgan, Edward P., 1967 - 1970 (Box 6 (33858), Folder 11)
    - Moses, Robert, 1971 (Box 6 (33858), Folder 12)
    - Moskin, Robert J., 1966 - 1977 (Box 6 (33858), Folder 13)
    - Moyers, Bill, 1971 - 1980 (Box 6 (33858), Folder 14)
    - Murrow, Edward R., 1964, n.d. (Box 6 (33858), Folder 15)
    - Murrow, Edward R. – regarding, 1966 - 1980 (Box 6 (33858), Folder 16)
    - N, miscellaneous, 1966 - 1980 (Box 6 (33858), Folder 17)
    - National Academy of Television Arts and Sciences, 1966 - 1970 (Box 6 (33858), Folder 18)
    - National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA), 1968 - 1971 (Box 6 (33858), Folder 19)
    - National Association of Educational Broadcasters, 1966 - 1978 (Box 6 (33858), Folder 20)
    - National Association of Television Executives, 1966 (Box 6 (33858), Folder 21)
    - National Broadcast Association for Community Affairs, 1978 (Box 6 (33858), Folder 22)
    - National Broadcasting Company (NBC), 1966 - 1980 (Box 6 (33858), Folder 23)
    - National Center for State Courts, 1977 (Box 6 (33858), Folder 24)
    - National Citizens Committee for Broadcasting, 1969 - 1977 (Box 6 (33858), Folder 25)
    - National Educational Television (NET) - Case, Everett, 1967 - 1969 (Box 6 (33858), Folder 26)
    - National Educational Television (NET) - Chamberlain, Ward B., 1970 - 1971 (Box 6 (33858), Folder 27)
    - National Educational Television (NET) - Day, James, 1969 - 1971 (Box 6 (33858), Folder 28-29)
    - National Educational Television (NET) - Iselin, John Jay, 1970 - 1971 (Box 6 (33858), Folder 30)
    - National Educational Television (NET) - Miscellaneous, 1966 - 1971 (Box 6 (33858), Folder 31-32)
    - National Educational Television (NET) - White, John F., 1966 - 1969 (Box 6 (33858), Folder 33-34)
    - National Endowment for the Humanities, 1977 - 1978 (Box 6 (33858), Folder 35)
    - National Friends of Public Broadcasting, 1970 (Box 6 (33858), Folder 36)
    - National News Council, 1977 - 1979 (Box 6 (33858), Folder 37)
    - National Public Affairs Center for Television, 1972 (Box 6 (33858), Folder 38)
    - National Public Radio, 1978 - 1980 (Box 6 (33858), Folder 39)
    - National Telecommunications and Information Administration, 1978 - 1979 (Box 6 (33858), Folder 40)
    - New York Herald Tribune, 1956 - 1964 (Box 7 (34189), Folder 1)
    - New York State Special Commission on Attica, 1972 (Box 7 (34189), Folder 2)
    - New York Times, 1966 - 1980 (Box 7 (34189), Folder 3-4)
    - New York University, 1966 - 1974 (Box 7 (34189), Folder 5)
    - The New Yorker – regarding profile of Friendly, 1962 (Box 7 (34189), Folder 6)
    - Newsweek, 1967 - 1971 (Box 7 (34189), Folder 7)
    - Nobbe, Tinka, 1970 - 1974 (Box 7 (34189), Folder 8)
    - O, miscellaneous (Box 7 (34189), Folder 9)
    - Opinion Research Corporation, 1966 - 1967 (Box 7 (34189), Folder 10)
    - Oppenheimer, Robert J., 1959 - 1962 (Box 7 (34189), Folder 11)
    - Oregon State University, 1968 - 1969 (Box 7 (34189), Folder 12)
    - Overseas Press Club, 1966 (Box 7 (34189), Folder 13)
    - P, miscellaneous, 1966 - 1980 (Box 7 (34189), Folder 14)
    - Pastore, John O., 1969 (Box 7 (34189), Folder 15)
    - Pincus, William, 1966 - 1967 (Box 7 (34189), Folder 16)
    - Powell, Lewis F., 1978 (Box 7 (34189), Folder 17)
    - Prince, Harold, 1968 (Box 7 (34189), Folder 18)
    - Public Broadcasting Service (PBS), 1970 - 1979 (Box 7 (34189), Folder 19-21)
    - Q, miscellaneous, 1966 - 1980 (Box 7 (34189), Folder 22)
    - R, miscellaneous, 1966 - 1980 (Box 7 (34189), Folder 23)
    - Radio Corporation of America (RCA), 1967 (Box 7 (34189), Folder 24)
    - Rand Corporation, 1968 - 1974 (Box 7 (34189), Folder 25)
    - Random House, 1968 - 1980 (Box 7 (34189), Folder 26)
    - Reeves Production Services, 1969 (Box 7 (34189), Folder 27)
    - Research and Design Institute, 1967 (Box 7 (34189), Folder 28)
    - Rivkin, Steven R., 1970 (Box 7 (34189), Folder 29)
    - Robinson, Hubbell, 1972 (Box 7 (34189), Folder 30)
    - Robinson, Marshall A., 1966 (Box 7 (34189), Folder 31)
    - Rogers, Ralph B., 1971 - 1979 (Box 7 (34189), Folder 32)
    - Rostow, Eugene V., 1969 (Box 7 (34189), Folder 33)
    - S, miscellaneous, 1966 - 1980 (Box 7 (34189), Folder 34-35)
    - Scheuer, Steven H., 1978 (Box 7 (34189), Folder 36)
    - Schorr, Daniel, 1976 - 1978 (Box 7 (34189), Folder 37)
    - Seward, James M., 1978 - 1979 (Box 7 (34189), Folder 38)
    - Shelby, Joyce, 1971 (Box 7 (34189), Folder 39)
    - Sheldon, Richard C., 1966 (Box 7 (34189), Folder 40)
    - Siegel, Seymour N., 1968 - 1971 (Box 7 (34189), Folder 41)
    - Slater, Gerry, 1967 - 1970 (Box 7 (34189), Folder 42)
    - Slater, Joseph E., 1966 (Box 7 (34189), Folder 43)
    - Sorabjee, Soli, 1978 - 1980 (Box 7 (34189), Folder 44)
    - Southern Educational Communications Association, 1980 (Box 7 (34189), Folder 45)
    - Stanford University, 1966 - 1979 (Box 7 (34189), Folder 46)
    - State of New Jersey Public Broadcasting Authority, 1971 (Box 7 (34189), Folder 47)
    - Stations - KCET (Los Angeles), 1966 - 1979 (Box 8 (34377), Folder 1-2)
    - Stations - KERA (Dallas), 1970 - 1979 (Box 8 (34377), Folder 3)
    - Stations - KQED (San Francisco), 1966 - 1978 (Box 8 (34377), Folder 4-9)
    - Stations - KQED (San Francisco) – Newsroom, 1970 - 1972 (Box 8 (34377), Folder 10)
    - Stations - KTCA (Twin Cities), 1974 - 1979 (Box 8 (34377), Folder 11)
    - Stations - Miscellaneous, 1966 - 1980 (Box 8 (34377), Folder 12)
    - Stations - Program Evaluations - Diamond, Edwin, 1971 - 1972 (Box 8 (34377), Folder 13)
    - Stations - Program Evaluations - Houseman, John, 1971 - 1972 (Box 8 (34377), Folder 14)
    - Stations - Program Evaluations - Lefkowitz, Bernard, 1972 - 1973 (Box 8 (34377), Folder 15)
    - Stations - Program Evaluations - Miscellaneous, 1971 - 1975 (Box 8 (34377), Folder 16)
    - Stations - Program Evaluations - Whiteside, Thomas, 1973 - 1974 (Box 8 (34377), Folder 17)
    - Stations - Program Evaluations - Wyatt, Hugh, 1972 (Box 8 (34377), Folder 18)
    - Stations - WBAI (New York), 1967 - 1977 (Box 8 (34377), Folder 19)
    - Stations - WETA (Washington, D.C.), 1966 - 1973 (Box 8 (34377), Folder 20-21)
    - Stations - WETA (Washington, D.C.), 1974 - 1980 (Box 9 (34442), Folder 1)
    - Stations - WFLD (Chicago), 1967 (Box 9 (34442), Folder 2)
    - Stations - WGBH (Boston), 1966 - 1980 (Box 9 (34442), Folder 3-7)
    - Stations - WHAS (Louisville), 1966 - 1967 (Box 9 (34442), Folder 8)
    - Stations - WHYY (Philadelphia), 1966 - 1978 (Box 9 (34442), Folder 9)
    - Stations - WJCT (Jacksonville), 1970 - 1975 (Box 9 (34442), Folder 10-11)
    - Stations - WNDT (New York), 1966 - 1969 (Box 9 (34442), Folder 12)
    - Stations - WNDT/WNET merger, 1969 - 1970 (Box 9 (34442), Folder 13)
    - Stations - WNET (New York), 1972 - 1980 (Box 9 (34442), Folder 14-19)
    - Stations - WNET – Murrow retrospective, 1971 - 1972 (Box 9 (34442), Folder 20)
    - Stations - WQED (Pittsburgh), 1969 - 1972 (Box 9 (34442), Folder 21)
    - Stations - WTVS (Detroit), 1968 - 1977 (Box 9 (34442), Folder 22)
    - Stations - WVIZ (Cleveland), 1969 - 1970 (Box 9 (34442), Folder 23)
    - Strasburg, Paul A., 1972 - 1974 (Box 9 (34442), Folder 24)
    - Stratton, Julius A., 1971 - 1972 (Box 9 (34442), Folder 25)
    - Sucherman, Stuart S., 1969 - 1980 (Box 9 (34442), Folder 26)
    - Sutton, Francis X., 1970 - 1976 (Box 10 (34453), Folder 1)
    - Sviridoff, Mitchell, 1968 - 1976 (Box 10 (34453), Folder 2)
    - Swing, Raymond, 1959 - 1969 (Box 10 (34453), Folder 3)
    - T, miscellaneous, 1966 - 1980 (Box 10 (34453), Folder 4)
    - Thomas, Franklin A., 1979 - 1980 (Box 10 (34453), Folder 5)
    - TNT Communications, 1966 (Box 10 (34453), Folder 6)
    - Townley, Richard, 1971 (Box 10 (34453), Folder 7)
    - Trottenberg, Arthur D., 1970 - 1979 (Box 10 (34453), Folder 8)
    - Tufts University – Edward R. Murrow Center of Public Diplomacy, 1968 - 1979 (Box 10 (34453), Folder 9-10)
    - Tuohy, Denis, 1967 (Box 10 (34453), Folder 11)
    - TV Guide, 1966 - 1967 (Box 10 (34453), Folder 12)
    - Twentieth Century Fund, 1969 - 1971 (Box 10 (34453), Folder 13)
    - Twentieth Century Fund – National News Council, 1972 - 1974 (Box 10 (34453), Folder 14-15)
    - U, miscellaneous, 1967 - 1980 (Box 10 (34453), Folder 16)
    - United Artists Corporation, 1968 (Box 10 (34453), Folder 17)
    - United Church of Christ, 1970 - 1979 (Box 10 (34453), Folder 18)
    - United Nations, 1970 (Box 10 (34453), Folder 19)
    - United Press International, 1966 (Box 10 (34453), Folder 20)
    - United States Information Agency, 1968 - 1969 (Box 10 (34453), Folder 21)
    - University of Notre Dame – Center for Civil Rights, 1976 - 1977 (Box 10 (34453), Folder 22)
    - University of Texas, 1966 - 1980 (Box 10 (34453), Folder 23)
    - U.S. News and World Report, 1971 - 1972 (Box 10 (34453), Folder 24)
    - V, miscellaneous, 1966 - 1980 (Box 10 (34453), Folder 25)
    - Van Ameringen Foundation, 1971 (Box 10 (34453), Folder 26)
    - Vanderbilt University, 1969 - 1980 (Box 10 (34453), Folder 27)
    - Vicas, George A., 1971 (Box 10 (34453), Folder 28)
    - W, miscellaneous, 1966 - 1980 (Box 10 (34453), Folder 29)
    - Ward, Champion F., 1970 - 1971 (Box 10 (34453), Folder 30)
    - Washington Post, 1967 - 1980 (Box 10 (34453), Folder 31)
    - Westinghouse Broadcasting Company, 1969 - 1979 (Box 10 (34453), Folder 32)
    - The White House, 1967 - 1979 (Box 10 (34453), Folder 33)
    - White, Stephen, 1967 (Box 10 (34453), Folder 34)
    - Wilkins, Roger, 1970 (Box 10 (34453), Folder 35)
    - Wiseman, Frederick, 1971 - 1979 (Box 10 (34453), Folder 36)
    - World Peace Foundation, 1967 (Box 10 (34453), Folder 37)
    - Xerox Corporation, 1968 - 1971 (Box 10 (34453), Folder 38)
    - Y, miscellaneous, 1966 - 1980 (Box 10 (34453), Folder 39)
    - Yale University, 1970 - 1980 (Box 10 (34453), Folder 40)
    - Z, miscellaneous, 1966 - 1980 (Box 10 (34453), Folder 41)
  - Chronological, 1971 - 1980; B
    - Chronological, 1971 - 1976 (Box 10 (34453), Folder 42-47)
    - Chronological, 1976 - 1980 (Box 11 (34655), Folder 1-13)
  - Personal, 1945 - 1979; C
    - Bernstein, Peter J., 1966 - 1967 (Box 11 (34655), Folder 14)
    - Fain family, 1955 - 1979 (Box 11 (34655), Folder 15)
    - Friendly, Andrew, 1968 - 1972 (Box 11 (34655), Folder 16)
    - Friendly, David, 1978 (Box 11 (34655), Folder 17)
    - Mark, Richard, 1974 (Box 11 (34655), Folder 18)
    - Miscellaneous chronological, 1954 - 1957 (Box 11 (34655), Folder 19-22)
    - Miscellaneous chronological, 1958 - 1970 (Box 12 (34657), Folder 1-10)
    - Riverdale Country School, 1966 - 1974 (Box 12 (34657), Folder 11-12)
    - Scarsdale Public Schools, 1968 (Box 12 (34657), Folder 13)
    - Stockbridge School, 1967 - 1970 (Box 12 (34657), Folder 14)
    - Summer camps, 1962 - 1970 (Box 12 (34657), Folder 15)
    - Wachenheimer, Therese, 1945 - 1957 (Box 12 (34657), Folder 16)
- Mayor's Advisory Task Force on CATV and Telecommunications, 1961-1971; II; 1.2 Cubic Feet
  Arrangement
  All documents are arranged chronologically.
  Correspondence, memoranda, agendas, reports, and meeting minutes documenting the work of this task force appointed by New York Mayor John V. Lindsay in 1967 and chaired by Fred W. Friendly. The group, which met during 1967-1968, investigated potential television interference created by the construction of the World Trade Center, evaluated existing community antenna television (CATV, or cable television) franchises in New York City and made recommendations concerning city government involvement in the development and operation of the local telecommunications infrastructure.
  - Chronological file, 1967 (Box 12 (34657), Folder 17-22)
  - Chronological file, 1967 - 1971 (Box 13 (34701), Folder 1-8)
- Media and Law Seminars, 1974-1980; III; 1.2 Cubic Feet
  Correspondence, memoranda, reports, publicity material and transcripts documenting a seminar series convened under Friendly's leadership to explore areas of conflict between the press and the courts. Prominent judges, lawyers and journalists met in cities across the country to discuss hypothetical court cases that highlighted tensions between the two groups, such as First Amendment protections and an individual's right to privacy. The subject area of the series was later broadened to include business and the media, human rights, terrorism and communications policy. More than 80 conferences were held over a seven year period.
  - Case studies, 1976 - 1980 (Box 13 (34701), Folder 9-11)
  - Chronological file, 1974 - 1980 (Box 13 (34701), Folder 12-18)
  - Fund for Media and the Law, 1976 (Box 13 (34701), Folder 19)
  - Handbook, undated (Box 14 (34777), Folder 1)
    Conditions Governing Access
    Not available.
    Custodial History
    Box 14 was not transferred to RAC.
  - Israel, 1979 - 1980 (Box 14 (34777), Folder 2)
  - Transcripts, 1976 - 1980 (Box 14 (34777), Folder 3-15)
- Photographs, 1950s-1970s; IV; 0.3 Cubic Feet
  Filed here are a few dozen photo prints and negatives of Fred W. Friendly, his colleagues and associates. Many were taken at public speaking engagements and Media and Law seminars. There are a few portrait photographs of Friendly, and several pictures of him with Edward R. Murrow during the years of their collaboration at CBS
  - Bundy, McGeorge, 1966, n.d. (Box 14 (34777), Folder 16)
  - Contact sheets, 1960s - 1970s (Box 14 (34777), Folder 17)
  - Friendly, Fred W., 1950s - 1970s (Box 14 (34777), Folder 18)
  - Friendly, Fred W. with Murrow, Edward R., undated (Box 14 (34777), Folder 19)
  - Negatives, 1960s - 1970s (Box 14 (34777), Folder 20)
- Speeches and Interviews, 1965-1980; V; 1.5 Cubic Feet
  Box 14 has not been transferred to RAC, therefore its contents are not currently available for scholarly research.
  If at some point in the future Box 14 is received by RAC, this material will then be made available for research.
  Transcripts, speaking notes, correspondence, publicity materials and news clippings regarding speeches and interviews by Friendly. Includes transcripts of testimony by Friendly at several U.S. Senate and House meetings on broadcast and telecommunications policy. Friendly also spoke frequently on issues related to freedom of the press and judicial restrictions on journalists. Files are arranged chronologically by date of speech or interview.
  - WCBS Radio interview, 1965 May 27 (Box 14 (34777), Folder 21)
  - American Society of Newspaper Editors, 1966 May 19 (Box 14 (34777), Folder 22)
  - National Broadcast Editorial Conference, 1966 July 29 (Box 14 (34777), Folder 23)
  - United States Senate Committee on Commerce Subcommittee on Communications testimony, 1966 August 17 (Box 14 (34777), Folder 24)
  - National Association of Educational Broadcasters, 1966 October 24 (Box 14 (34777), Folder 25)
  - Chicago speech, 1967 March 8 (Box 14 (34777), Folder 26)
  - WNEW Radio interview, 1967 March 26 (Box 14 (34777), Folder 27)
  - WNDT Radio interview, 1967 March 27 (Box 14 (34777), Folder 28)
  - WHYY Television interview, 1967 May 1 (Box 14 (34777), Folder 29)
  - United States Senate Committee on Commerce Subcommittee on Communications testimony, 1967 April 12 (Box 14 (34777), Folder 30)
  - U.S. News and World Report interview, 1967 May 8 (Box 14 (34777), Folder 31)
  - Nichols College commencement, 1967 June 2 (Box 14 (34777), Folder 32)
  - International Press Institute, 1967 June 21 (Box 14 (34777), Folder 33)
  - Granada Guildhall Lecture, 1967 October 24 (Box 15 (34785), Folder 1)
  - National Council of Teachers of English, 1968 November 28 (Box 15 (34785), Folder 2)
  - Stockbridge School Commencement, 1969 June 8 (Box 15 (34785), Folder 3)
  - Pittsburgh Conference on Media and Minorities, 1969 November 14 (Box 15 (34785), Folder 4)
  - World Mental Health Assembly, 1969 November 19 (Box 15 (34785), Folder 5)
  - California Institute of Technology, 1969 November 21 (Box 15 (34785), Folder 6)
  - Indiana Civil Liberties Union, 1970 January 24 (Box 15 (34785), Folder 7)
  - Massachusetts Institute of Technology, 1970 February 25 (Box 15 (34785), Folder 8)
  - U.S. House of Representatives Interstate and Foreign Commerce Committee Subcommittee on Communications and Power testimony, 1970 April 27 (Box 15 (34785), Folder 9)
  - American Jewish Congress, 1970 May 22 (Box 15 (34785), Folder 10)
  - Public Relations Society of America, 1970 November 16 (Box 15 (34785), Folder 11)
  - Greensboro Chamber of Commerce, 1971 January 5 (Box 15 (34785), Folder 12)
  - University of Michigan, 1971 March 10 (Box 15 (34785), Folder 13)
  - Tufts University, 1971 April 16 (Box 15 (34785), Folder 14)
  - Kenyon College, 1971 April 28 (Box 15 (34785), Folder 15)
  - University of Wisconsin commencement, 1971 June 14 (Box 15 (34785), Folder 16)
  - U.S. Senate Committee on the Judiciary Subcommittee on Constitutional Rights testimony, 1971 October 12 (Box 15 (34785), Folder 17)
  - Federacion Publicataria de Puerto Rico, 1971 November 5-6 (Box 15 (34785), Folder 18)
  - Publi-Cable Inc. conference, 1972 May 5 (Box 15 (34785), Folder 19)
  - National Press Club Luncheon, 1972 June 1 (Box 15 (34785), Folder 20)
  - Riverdale School commencement, 1972 June 9 (Box 15 (34785), Folder 21)
  - Bronxville, NY, 1973 January 23 (Box 15 (34785), Folder 22)
  - Northwest Broadcast News Association, 1973 February 2 (Box 15 (34785), Folder 23)
  - CBS 60 Minutes, 1973 March 25 (Box 15 (34785), Folder 24)
  - American Civil Liberties Union, 1973 May 23 (Box 15 (34785), Folder 25)
  - National Magazine Awards, 1973 May 24 (Box 15 (34785), Folder 26)
  - Cleveland City Club, 1973 December 21 (Box 15 (34785), Folder 27)
  - Federal Communications Bar Association, 1974 January 10 (Box 15 (34785), Folder 28)
  - Salzburg Seminar in American Studies, 1974 March (Box 15 (34785), Folder 29)
  - U.S. Congress Joint Committee on Congressional Operations, 1974 April 9 (Box 15 (34785), Folder 30)
  - Northwestern University, 1974 June 15 (Box 15 (34785), Folder 31)
  - U.S. Senate Committee on Finance, 1974 September 10 (Box 15 (34785), Folder 32)
  - Practicing Law Institute Seminar, 1974 November 14 (Box 15 (34785), Folder 33)
  - Joint University Libraries Dinner, Nashville, 1974 November 25 (Box 15 (34785), Folder 34)
  - Boston Community Media Council, 1975 January 9 (Box 15 (34785), Folder 35)
  - University of Texas at Austin, 1975 March 1 (Box 15 (34785), Folder 36)
  - Judicial Conference for the First Circuit, 1975 May 13 (Box 15 (34785), Folder 37)
  - Public Communication Foundation for North Texas, 1975 September 18 (Box 15 (34785), Folder 38)
  - Chief Executives Forum, Lake Placid NY, 1975 October 1 (Box 15 (34785), Folder 39)
  - NBC Tomorrow, 1976 February 19 (Box 15 (34785), Folder 40)
  - National Council of Jewish Women, 1976 October 19 (Box 15 (34785), Folder 41)
  - U.S. Military Academy, West Point NY, 1978 March 6 (Box 15 (34785), Folder 42)
  - National Conference on State Courts, 1978 March 20 (Box 15 (34785), Folder 43)
  - Franklin N. Flaschner Judicial Institute, 1978 June 8 (Box 15 (34785), Folder 44)
  - American Jewish Congress, 1978 June 21 (Box 15 (34785), Folder 45)
  - U.S. House of Representatives Interstate and Foreign Commerce Committee Subcommittee on Communications testimony, 1978 September 26 (Box 15 (34785), Folder 46)
  - Minnesota Historical Society, 1978 October 12 (Box 15 (34785), Folder 47)
  - Phillips Petroleum Management Seminar, 1978 October 27 (Box 15 (34785), Folder 48)
  - WGBH Television interview, 1979 February 20 (Box 15 (34785), Folder 49)
  - University of Oregon, 1979 April 16 (Box 15 (34785), Folder 50)
  - Brown University, 1980 March 18 (Box 15 (34785), Folder 51)
- Subjects, 1958-1980; VI; 6.6 Cubic Feet
  Correspondence, memoranda, agendas, reports and research materials compiled by Friendly on a variety of topics relating to broadcasting, telecommunications, journalism and law. There are substantial files on the early design and implementation of community antenna television (CATV, or cable television) systems, especially in the New York City region, satellite broadcast technology, and the Foundation-funded operations of public television stations and organizations including National Educational Television (NET) and the Public Broadcast Laboratory. Reports and memos from the Office of Public Broadcasting and Office of Communications (box 19, folders 8-12) illuminate staff thinking during the period when Foundation support for public television was dramatically reduced.
  Files are arranged alphabetically.
  - Accuracy in Media – Pensions complaint, 1973 - 1974 (Box 15 (34785), Folder 52)
  - The Advocates, 1969 - 1973 (Box 15 (34785), Folder 53)
  - Alaska, 1969 - 1970 (Box 15 (34785), Folder 54)
  - Aspen Institute Conference on Public Television, 1975 (Box 15 (34785), Folder 55)
  - Association of American Publishers, 1975 (Box 15 (34785), Folder 56)
  - Audience research, 1971 - 1972 (Box 16 (34796), Folder 1)
  - Bay Area Educational Television Association, 1971 (Box 16 (34796), Folder 2)
  - Bedford-Stuyvesant Television, 1967 (Box 16 (34796), Folder 3)
  - Biographical information on Fred W. Friendly, circa 1968 (Box 16 (34796), Folder 4)
  - Board of Trustees, 1968 - 1976 (Box 16 (34796), Folder 5)
  - Board of Trustees – Broadcasting Committee, 1968 - 1972 (Box 16 (34796), Folder 6)
  - Board of Trustees – Communications Committee, 1976 - 1979 (Box 16 (34796), Folder 7)
  - Broadcasting grants, historical list of, 1973 (Box 16 (34796), Folder 8)
  - Building Use Committee, 1977 - 1979 (Box 16 (34796), Folder 9)
  - Cable Television Information Center, 1972 - 1977 (Box 16 (34796), Folder 10)
  - Calendars, 1966 - 1967 (Box 16 (34796), Folder 11)
  - Cameras in courtrooms, 1979 (Box 16 (34796), Folder 12)
  - Carnegie Commission on Educational Television, 1966-1971 (Box 16 (34796), Folder 13)
  - Carnegie Study of the Education of Educators, 1966 - 1967 (Box 16 (34796), Folder 14)
  - Children's Television Workshop, 1972 (Box 16 (34796), Folder 15)
  - Children's Television Workshop – Arabic pilot project, 1975 - 1976 (Box 16 (34796), Folder 16)
  - Childs, Marquis W. – interview transcripts, undated (Box 16 (34796), Folder 17)
  - Citizens Communications Center, 1979 (Box 16 (34796), Folder 18)
  - CBS Reports – transcripts, 1961 - 1963 (Box 16 (34796), Folder 19)
  - CBS Reports – "The Selling of the Pentagon,", 1971 (Box 16 (34796), Folder 20)
  - Columbia University – Journalism and the First Amendment course, 1976 - 1977 (Box 16 (34796), Folder 21)
  - Columbia University – School of Journalism Summer Program, 1968 - 1971 (Box 16 (34796), Folder 22)
  - Commission on Cable Communications, 1970 (Box 16 (34796), Folder 23)
  - Commission on Federal Communications Policy, 1975 (Box 16 (34796), Folder 24)
  - Comstock, George A., 1974 (Box 16 (34796), Folder 25)
  - Communications Act of 1978 (Box 16 (34796), Folder 26)
  - Communications Act of 1978 – Briefing materials (Box 16 (34796), Folder 27)
  - Communications policy seminar, 1979 (Box 16 (34796), Folder 28)